## SENIOR PRODUCT MANAGER

Summary

Resourceful, honest, empathetic product manager with years of all around web and mobile product experience. Believer that engineers are magicians and is products job to help everyone love their wonderful tricks by releasing fun, customer-focused products. Skills

- Agile Development, Scrum, Kanban, Mobile, iOS, Android, Lean Start-up Methodology
- Digital Media Trends, Analytics, Curiosity, Emerging Platform Insights, Leading Edge Thinker, Lynchpin

## Experience

Senior Product Manager Feb 2013 to Current

Nice Systems il/4 Denver, CO

- Directly led team of 10 engineers as a product owner responsible for creating awarding-winning iOS sports and entertainment apps BUNT, HUDDLE, KICK and Star Wars: Card Trader.
- Apps combined 2015 year-to-date free-to-play revenues in excess of \$20M, up 150% from \$8M in 2014 and 900% from \$2M in 2013.
- Lead team to establish Topps as a Top 50 iOS game publisher by revenue in the US.
- Conceived and implemented popular collectible card game loops with one of a kind, real-time fantasy sports game play to create a new paradigm of "Role-playing Game meets Fantasy Sports".
- Worked directly with licensors: The Premier League, Bundesliga, UEFA, Major League Baseball, National Football League and Lucasfilm/Disney to ensure compliance and quality of treatment of IP.
- Established operational best practices, built internal dashboards for real-time operations, lead marketing initiatives and assumed leadership role in Topps Digital organization as team grew from 7 to 25 team members.

Product Manager Feb 2011 to Feb 2013 Google Inc. ï¼ Santa Barbara , CA

- Backlog and prioritization manager of ATG based Blaze e-Commerce platform powering all Oberon Media partner websites.
- Designed, developed, and managed integration of three major product initiatives: online games, video ads and full front end redesign of Iplay games.
- Products launched responsible for an additional \$70k revenue per month.
- Spearheaded implementation of Google Analytics, Adwords, e-Commerce event tracking across all of I-play.
- Product lead for all SEO related items for Blaze platform.
- Increased SEO traffic from 5% to 10% of total traffic.

Social Media Strategist, Social Product Manager Jan 2006 to Jan 2011

Fis il/4 Winchester, MA

- Strategically and tactically developed and implemented Games.com social media strategy.
- Founded Games.com Blog which grew 800k monthly UVs in 18 months.
- Launched Games.com Fan page currently has 93k fans with over 1.2m monthly impressions.
- Product Manager on all SEO related web development.
- Consultant on all AOL Games properties for SEO.
- Maintain expertise of trends and best practices in digital technology, social media and integrated marketing.
- Consulted on final launch viability of all projects.
- Strategically advise ad-sales pitches.
- Conceptualized Game of the Day on Games.com lead to 2 million dollar buy.
- Self-starter on Search Engine Optimization on Games.com.
- Product Manager on all SEO related web development.
- Consultant on all AOL Games properties for SEO.

Senior Product Owner Jul 2016 to Current

Greenlit Content i1/4 City, STATE

**Education and Training** 

BA, History May 1997 Binghamton University, State University of New York History

Skills

Premier, ads, ad-sales, Agile, AOL, brand management, com, Consultant, content, e-Commerce, Edge, editorial, finance, Google Analytics, IP, leadership, marketing, publisher, page, Product Manager, quality, real-time, Scrum, Search Engine Optimization, Self-starter, strategy, video, web development, web development, websites